<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>lou1306</title>
    <link>http://lou1306.github.io/en/</link>
    <description>Recent content on lou1306</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>it-it</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 07 Jul 2021 11:24:46 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://lou1306.github.io/en/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Bounded model checking with CBMC and Glucose</title>
      <link>http://lou1306.github.io/en/post/2020-12-10-cbmc-and-glucose/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Dec 2020 22:09:07 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lou1306.github.io/en/post/2020-12-10-cbmc-and-glucose/</guid>
      <description>Formal verification allows to find bugs in a program by systematically exploring all its feasible executions. I have used several formal verification tools during my PhD; since I feel there is a lack of technical blog posts about this topic on the Web, I&amp;rsquo;ll try and write some :)
This post deals with bounded model checking, specifically the CBMC tool and how to combine it with the Glucose solver. I believe this leads to a measurable increase in performance, at least when checking unsafe programs.<a href='http://lou1306.github.io/en/post/2020-12-10-cbmc-and-glucose/'><em>Continue</em></a></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thoughts on recording talks</title>
      <link>http://lou1306.github.io/en/post/2020-10-19-talks/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Oct 2020 12:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lou1306.github.io/en/post/2020-10-19-talks/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The tool paper that originated my previous post on &lt;a href=&#34;../../post/2020-01-02-demos/&#34;&gt;demo videos&lt;/a&gt;
got accepted. Hooray!
Given the ongoing global pandemic, I was asked to submit a 15-minute video of my
presentation, that has then been broadcasted to all participants.
This post is a collection of notes I gathered along the way.&lt;/p&gt;<a href='http://lou1306.github.io/en/post/2020-10-19-talks/'><em>Continue</em></a></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Naming of Tools</title>
      <link>http://lou1306.github.io/en/post/2020-06-02-namingoftools/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Jun 2020 12:59:09 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lou1306.github.io/en/post/2020-06-02-namingoftools/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Naming of Tools is a tough nail to hammer,&lt;br&gt;
It isn’t just one of your parity games;&lt;br&gt;
But I wonder why each and every programmer&lt;br&gt;
always comes up with THE USUAL TWO NAMES.&lt;/p&gt;<a href='http://lou1306.github.io/en/post/2020-06-02-namingoftools/'><em>Continue</em></a></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Writing LaTeX in 2020: survival notes</title>
      <link>http://lou1306.github.io/en/post/2020-05-26-latex/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lou1306.github.io/en/post/2020-05-26-latex/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This post will be part of a collection of notes about the way I currently deal
with LaTeX documents.
It is not a &amp;ldquo;for dummies&amp;rdquo; guide: some tools and extensions need a bit of
configuration, and the user should already be familiar with LaTeX and some of
its inner workings.
I do feel that this setup allows an experienced user to become more
productive in the long term, especially when dealing with a large document or
with multiple documents at the same time.&lt;/p&gt;<a href='http://lou1306.github.io/en/post/2020-05-26-latex/'><em>Continue</em></a></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thoughts on tool demo videos</title>
      <link>http://lou1306.github.io/en/post/2020-01-02-demos/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lou1306.github.io/en/post/2020-01-02-demos/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Recently I had to produce a demo video as part of a tool paper submission.
Here are some notes I gathered in the process: they might be useful
to my future self or to other wannabe videomakers.&lt;/p&gt;<a href='http://lou1306.github.io/en/post/2020-01-02-demos/'><em>Continue</em></a></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Digital signing your physical stuff</title>
      <link>http://lou1306.github.io/en/post/2019-01-02-signing/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Jan 2019 18:02:11 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lou1306.github.io/en/post/2019-01-02-signing/</guid>
      <description>With the new year comes a new daily notebook! Since I always carry it around, I typically put a lot of personal data in the first pages of the notebook in the hope that, should I lose it somewhere, it will be found and returned. This time, as I was filling in the info page, I started thinking&amp;hellip; Wouldn&amp;rsquo;t it be nice if I had some other way to prove that this thing is mine, without having to provide so much information?<a href='http://lou1306.github.io/en/post/2019-01-02-signing/'><em>Continue</em></a></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>C: Packing two integers in a single variable</title>
      <link>http://lou1306.github.io/en/post/2018-01-11-packing/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Jan 2018 11:56:11 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lou1306.github.io/en/post/2018-01-11-packing/</guid>
      <description>Lately we needed to put a pair of small integers into a single int variable. (Let us gloss over the intricacies of what an int actually is and just assume it is 32-bit, shall we?) Nothing crazy hard but still, it took some trial and error before we got it right. So, if anybody needs it or is just curious, here&amp;rsquo;s the code:
 The code will test all possible tuples and quit if some unpacking gives an unexpected result.<a href='http://lou1306.github.io/en/post/2018-01-11-packing/'><em>Continue</em></a></description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
